Tom Antony Nidhin

16 Castlegate Downs Adamstown Lucan Co. Dublin K78 XT95

0834277677
nidhintom@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-nidhin/

SUMMARY

An experienced and qualified Facilities Manager, with a vast knowledge of various sectors including operations, asset management and contract management.

Extensive experience in both project and budget management, alongside a strong health & safety

A knowledgeable and focused individual with excellent organization and leadership skills with experience in supervising and management.

Critical thinker – Ability to take ownership of issues and to work alone with little or no supervision.

Fully aware of compliance with company quality and operational policies and procedures.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SODEXO – Technological University Dublin (TUD)

Jul 2019 - Present

Facility Manager (Sodexo -KTCS)

June 2021- Present

- Leading the contract ensuring standards are set and delivered, talent and resources
 are utilised optimally, client relationships are nurtured and developed. All opportunities
 for best practise and capability growth are leveraged.
- Delivering on financial and operational target Ensuring that committed targets are met or exceeded and that costs & revenues are closely managed.
- Selecting, managing, engaging and developing highly performing and diverse operating teams with the right skills and capabilities.
- Deployment of account strategy and ensuring that effective plans are in place to deliver against strategy.
- Planning and coordinating all installation and refurbishments.
- Managing the upkeep of the equipment and supplies to meet health and safety standards.
- Inspecting building structure to determine the need for repairs or renovations.
- Ensuring basic facilities like Water and Heating are well maintained.
- Manage day to day contract workers on site with the services provided.
- Allocating and managing the space between the rooms.
- Asset management and BIM management.
- Maintain ongoing communication with contractors, clients and team.

Facility Coordinator (Sodexo - TUD)

Jul 2019 - June 2021

- Leading activities around performance planning and evaluation advice.
- Mobilization of helpdesk systems and BMS in the Grangegorman TU Dublin contract.
- Auditing, gathering and analysing data in order to report on the performance of KPIs for the TU Dublin campus accounts against Service level agreements.
- Establishing performance monitoring indicators for each service and compliance checking for each service.
- Carrying audits against service standards.
- Identifying and resolving potential service performance shortfalls and instances of unavailability.
- Collaborating with managers in reviewing data from the operational system and assisting in developing improvement plans.
- Acting as a pro- active subject matter expert for senior management and other relevant stakeholders.
- Producing month end report for the authority by gathering data from BMS, CAFM and E-Cat system.
- Design and lead progressive initiatives around capacity building of workforce incl. planning, facilitation of training and workshops.
- Approval of SAP invoices for the TU Dublin accounts.

ECS Recruitment

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

Senior Recruitment Consultant

- Screening candidates and drawing up shortlists of candidates for clients to interview
- Managing and growing portfolio of clients
- Building relationship between candidates and clients
- Managing full recruitment process
- Interviewing and assessing prospective applicants and matching them with vacancies as client companies
- Helping applicants to prepare for interview
- Holding open days for job seekers where more information is provided about the company and registration of interest is completed
- Attending exhibitions and networking meetings
- Sales calls and business development

Tom Antony Nidhin

16 Castlegate Downs
Adamstown
Lucan, Co. Dublin
K78 XT95

0834277677
nidhintom@gmail.com

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Staff management
Contract management
Technical Recruiting
First Aid
Microsoft Tools Professiona
Exercising and Health Care
Team Sports

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Clarity Locums

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

Recruitment Consultant

- Sourcing high quality candidates via company database, social media, job board and referrals
- Advertising vacancies on job boards
- Screening and shortlisting candidates
- Conducting phone interviews
- Setting up F2F interviews between the client and the candidates
- Building strong relationships with candidates and clients
- Referencing candidates to ensure quality and suitability
- Following up on feedback from relevant parities

Your Smile Direct

March 2017 - Oct 2018

In- House Recruiter/ Trainee HR

- Developing and implementing organizational recruiting strategies to attract the best qualified candidates
- Conduct interviews by evaluating employment factors such as job experience, education, training, skills, knowledge, abilities and other data relevant to the selection process
- Preparing, extend and negotiate competitive job offers
- Keep HR Business partners and hiring managers updated as appropriate while effectively interacting with all levels of employees, answering questions and providing information
- General administration when required, excellent telephone communication skills
- Keeping up to date with legislation and practices within the industry
- Contact references and perform background checks
- Processing paperwork for new starters
- Inform applicants about job details such as benefits and conditions
- Preparation of staff handbooks

Konkan Indian Restaurant

March 2016 - Dec 2016

Front Office Coordinator

- Coordinating daily front of house and back of house restaurant operations
- Responding efficiently and accurately to customer complaint
- Organising and supervising shifts
- Regularly review product quality and research new vendors
- Estimate future needs of goods, kitchen utensils and cleaning products
- Ensure compliance with sanitisation and safety regulation

Education and Qualification

Leaving Cert | June 2012

Institute of Education, Dublin

BA(Hons) Human Resource Management Strategy and Practice, Level 8 | 2020

National College of Ireland, Dublin